Dickson Kinyua

Front End Web Developer

dickykinyua@gmail.com

Kenya, Africa

Summary

With over one year of experience in Front End development, I specialize in building high performance web applications using Tailwind and ReactJS. My projects have consistently resulted in improved performance and user satisfaction. I bring a proactive approach to technical innovation.

Experience

Junior Front End Developer

10/01/2024-Present

Atilead

- ➤ Joined a team of 3 in developing a high performance single-page application using ReactJS reducing loading time by 30%.
- Implemented responsive and accessible design, ensuring compatibility across multiple devices and browsers, boosting user engagement by 25%.
- > Developed and maintained code quality through rigorous testing and debugging.

Front End Developer

15/02/2024 -present

Shopi

- Collaborated with design teams to integrate user interfaces into scalable web applications boosting user satisfaction.
- Enhanced system accessibility and responsiveness, leading to a 10% increase in daily active users.
- Contributed to the selection and implementation of front-end frameworks

<u>Skills</u>

- > HTML5
- > CSS/Tailwind
- JavaScript-ReactJS
- ➤ Node-Js
- Express
- ➤ MongoDB

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Meru University of Science and Technology 2016-2020

Referees

1. Caxton Muthoni-Software Engineer

0743751575

2. Immanuel Maina- Software Engineer

0791608150